Victor Danilchenko

4 Willimansett st. South Hadley, MA 01075 (413) 534-0919 victor@danilchenko.net

OBJECTIVE: Senior technical management position where my diverse background and experience will add value to the operation.

PRECIS

I am a software engineer by training, with a good deal of both theoretical and practical knowledge. I am extremely self-motivated, capable of carrying a task from conception through architecture, implementation, and support. I have experience leading technical development of complex web and IT projects. Possessing proficiency with a broad array of environments and technologies, and experience with technical architecture and management, I can leverage my excellent problem-solving and communication skills towards addressing a wide variety of problems, and can readily translate back and forth between technical requirements and non-technical user needs.

SYSTEMS

Servers: UNIX, Windows, Mac OS/X

Clustering: High-performance, high-availability

Cloud computing: Amazon EC2

SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGIES

APIs and Toolkits: Ajax, LAMP, CGI, mod_perl, Mason, Flash, Cocoa, Win32, Xlib, Tk **Programming languages:** Perl, PHP, HTML, ActionScript2, C++, Objective-C, C, Lisp, ML, Pascal, Fortran, Basic, Assembler (PC), Bourne Shell, C Shell, JCL

Database technologies: SQL, Perl/DBI, Dbase IV, POET

EMPLOYMENT

2007-present Chief Technical Officer, AskOnline

- Led development effort for Software-as-a-Service solution that scaled to over 300,000 users with a highly efficient infrastructure backend
- Was lead evaluator of third party systems, integrated several into the SaaS platform
- Oversaw platform integration with the clients' IT infrastructure (ADS, LDAP, SSO, etc.))
- Deployed the sales support infrastructure, oversaw its integration with third-party analytics services
- Managed customer support for hundreds of clients, achieving 99.99% uptime
- Performed product evangelism and outreach, attending multiple conferences

2005-2007 Senior Software Engineer, AskOnline

- Developed the SaaS application in the LAMP framework
- Was lead evaluator of third party systems, integrated several into the SaaS platform
- Integrated with the clients' IT infrastructure (ADS, LDAP, SSO, etc.)
- Administered the server backend for the SaaS deployment

1997-2005 Software Specialist, University of Massachusetts/Amherst

- Performed system administration for over 1800 Windows, Unix, and Mac clients and servers
- Performed end-user technical and operations support for a 400-member department, 45 research labs and administrative groups
- Primary in-house software developer for the department support group (5 applications)
- Implemented and supported various client/server technologies, such as LDAP, NIS, SQL, mail, web, and the SSL infrastructure

1996-1998 **Research Assistant**, RBR lab, Umass/Amherst

- Performed AI research at Resource-Bounded Reasoning Laboratory, coauthored and contributed to 3 publications
- Researched the theoretic aspects of 'anytime' algorithms

1995-1996 Software Engineer, DRMA Inc., New York, NY

- Key member of commercial media-buying software development team
- Designed user interface and the DB abstraction layer
- Programmed in Visual C++ under Windows 3.1, 95, NT
- Provided technical advice for corporate sales

EDUCATION

2002 MS in Computer Science, University of Massachusetts

1996 BS in Computer Science, PACE University (Summa Cum Laude)

LANGUAGES

English, Russian, Ukrainian

REFERENCES

Available upon request